<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Encoding Guidelines for Lawforms Project</title>
            <author>Elizabeth Williamson</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>ERC Lawforms Project encoding guidelines, 2018-22</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Born digital</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
         <docTitle>
            <titlePart>Encoding Guidelines for Lawforms Project</titlePart>
         </docTitle>
      </front>
      <body>
         <lb/>
         <div>
            <head>Project Description</head>
            <p>The aim is to encode 50-100 legal texts (with an upper limit of 200). As of June
               2019, these are likely to include 60 so far transcribed (but to varying quality) and
               10-20 texts that are currently PDFs on Asnad.</p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <head>TEIheader and metadata</head>
            <p>Fill in the spaces for title, editor etc marked with comments in the template
               document.</p>
            <div>
               <head>Id number for the document</head>
               <p><emph>Every document needs to have a unique <att>xml:id</att> on the <gi>TEI</gi>
                     element.</emph> This should be a unique, abbreviated version of the shelfmark
                  and repository, or some similar format, preceded by lf for Lawforms. Use the
                  same identifier for the filename, and for the filename for any related images
                  (including page numbers as needed). The filename is constructed by: lf_[repository
                  abbreviation]_[shelfmark or ID number] - you can use camelCase if any of these
                  sections have multiple words. You may also include an indication of the collection
                  to which the manuscript belongs, and date, in the middle of the filename if
                  relevant, as in the second example: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <TEI xml:id="lf_pDas_1661_brd_ac"> </TEI>
                     <TEI xml:id="lf_hamdani_1850_01"> </TEI>
                  </egXML>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Source and Manuscript description</head>
               <p>Use the <gi>msDesc</gi> element in the TEI header to provide additional details on
                  the manuscript and its contents. This will include responsitory/shelfmark
                  information. If there is no shelfmark, eg private archive, write 'no shelfmark' in
                  the <gi>idno</gi> tag, since this is for recording the shelfmark given by the
                  repository. If the manuscript is part of a collection, even one dispersed across
                  multiple archives, add this in collection and ensure there is an entry in the
                  archival collections list in repositories file. For example: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <msDesc>
                        <msIdentifier>
                           <repository ref="#bibliothequeMunicipale"/>
                           <collection ref="#pDas"/>
                           <idno>Shelfmark or manuscript number goes here, including folio reference
                              if relevant, or 'no shelfmark'</idno>
                        </msIdentifier>
                     </msDesc>
                  </egXML></p>
               <p>When you encounter a new repository, add it to the repositories list in
                  bibliography.xml and use its xml id to provide the <att>ref</att> for the
                  manuscript description in the header.</p>
               <p>If the source of the document is a publication rather than a manuscript, add this
                  in <gi>bibl</gi> before the <gi>msDesc</gi>; if there is both a publication and
                  the original manuscript, you can record both; if there is only a publication
                  extant, delete the <gi>msDesc</gi> section.</p>

               <p>Include whether the document is original/authorized copy/unauthorized copy, if
                  known, in the <gi>history</gi> section, in <gi>objectType</gi>.</p>
               <p>Include the date of the document in the manuscript description section, within
                     <gi>history</gi>. You may provide several calendars if wanted, but you should
                  also provide a default translation to the Gregorian calendar, with <att>when</att>
                  given in standardized (gregorian) format: </p>
               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><history>
                     <origin>
                        <origDate calendar="#julus">9 Jumadi I 1071</origDate>
                        <origDate calendar="#gregorian" when="1661-01-10">10 Jan 1661</origDate>
                     </origin>
                  </history>
               </egXML>
               <p>If it's not clear what date it is, you can provide date ranges, for example:
                     <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><date calendar="#gregorian"
                        notBefore="1650" notAfter="1700">the second half of the seventeenth
                        century</date></egXML></p>
               <p>Date ranges can also include months, for example:
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><date calendar="#gregorian"
                     notBefore="1735-05" notAfter="1736-05">Between May 1735 and May 1736</date></egXML></p>
               <p>You can provide a partial date in the standardized <att>when</att> attribute if
                  relevant, e.g. <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><date
                        calendar="#gregorian" when="--09">septembre</date>
                     <date calendar="#gregorian" when="1980-02">early February
                  1980</date></egXML></p>
               <p>Possible calendar values: bengali, fasli, gregorian, hijri-qamri, hijri-shamsi,
                  jovian_brihaspati, julian, julus, maghi, samvat, samvat-chaitradi,
                  samvat-shravanadi, shaka, suhur, turkish.</p>
               <p>You can also provide a place of issue and place of receipt if wanted/relevant,
                  with <att>ref</att> refering to their xml:id in the places file (see below);
                  delete these if not relevant: <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"
                        ><origDate calendar="#gregorian" when="1000-01-01">Example date</origDate>
                     <origPlace type="placeOfIssue" ref="#example"/>
                     <origPlace type="placeOfReceipt" ref="#example"/></egXML>
               </p>
               <p>If the manuscript is published, you can add the bibliographic reference in
                     <gi>additional</gi>, following the <gi>history</gi> section, within
                     <gi>msDesc</gi>. In a <gi>ref</gi> tag (with type=bibl) add a reference to the
                  book in the bibliography file (add an entry there if it doesn't yet exist). Add
                  page numbers or similar reference as <gi>biblScope</gi> as follows: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <additional>
                        <listBibl>
                           <bibl type="academic" n="#foner1945_collectedThomasPaine">
                              <biblScope>pp.1-2</biblScope>
                           </bibl>
                        </listBibl>
                     </additional>
                  </egXML></p>

            </div>


            <div>
               <head>Text categories, keywords, summary, participant roles</head>
               <p><hi>Functional type</hi>: Each text will be assigned to a category that describes the actual function of the document, eg imperial and
                  royal decrees. This is your interpretive judgement.</p>
               <p><hi>Formal type</hi>: Each text may also be assigned to a category that describes
                  the formal status or appearance of the document, for example, a document might
                  state that it is a declaration of victory. This is not an interpretive judgement
                  but rather a description of the form of the document.</p>
               <p><hi>Thematic keywords</hi>: Each text is assigned one or several thematic keywords.</p>
               <p>Both of these should use controlled vocabulary listed below. Use the profile description in the TEI header, as follows: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <profileDesc>
                        <textClass>
                           <keywords scheme="#functional">
                              <term key="privateDeeds"/>
                              <!-- NOTE: put the larger category first -->
                              <term key="sales"/>
                           </keywords>
                           <keywords scheme="#formal">
                              <term key="farman"/>
                           </keywords>
                           <keywords scheme="#thematic">
                              <term>Women</term>
                           </keywords>
                        </textClass>
                     </profileDesc>
                  </egXML></p>
               <p>Formal and functional categories, and keywords, are listed in the Taxonomy document. Ensure that
                  the primary name in the taxonomy list is marked by role=default (usually Persian),
                  and add further details to form the essay pages as preferred: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <item xml:id="farighKhatti">
                        <name xml:lang="per" role="default">Farigh Khatti</name>
                        <name xml:lang="hin">Pharkhati</name>
                        <name xml:lang="eng">Quittance deed</name>
                        <note>Detailed description here</note>
                        <!--    further reading -->
                        <listBibl>
                           <bibl type="academic" n="#exampleFromBibliographyFile"/>
                        </listBibl>
                     </item>
                  </egXML>
               </p>
               <p>You must provide a concise summary for each document transcribed. Include this in
                  the <gi>abstract</gi> section. Use <gi>note</gi> to add information that apply to
                  the whole document, e.g. academic citations. <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><abstract>
                        <p>Example summary here. Ideally, these should be similar lengths, though
                           this isn't essential - would you aim for a small paragraph? Try to also
                           have an agreed style/tone. <note>For discussion of the transactions
                              leading to the issuance of this imperial order, inlcluding Zulfiqar
                              Khan's earlier grant of a <ref type="glossary" target="#gl_qaul"
                                 >qaul-nama</ref> to Shahu, see <ref type="bibl"
                                 target="#sarkar1952">Sarkar, History of Aurangzib, Vol. 5, pp.
                                 81-2</ref>.</note>
                        </p></abstract></egXML>
               </p>
               <p>Include a participant description to describe the roles of the people in the
                  document. To see how to mark up names with correct IDs etc, see Names section.
                     <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <particDesc>
                        <person role="buyer">
                           <persName ref="#shahBeg">Shah Beg</persName>
                        </person>
                        <person role="seller">
                           <persName ref="#mohammadSonOfYassein">Mohammad</persName>
                        </person>
                     </particDesc>
                  </egXML> Possible roles include: arbitrator, buyer, creditor, debtor, guarantor,
                  grantor, grantee, heir, issuer, recipient, judge, mortgager, seller, supplicant,
                  witness, writer, litigant.</p>

            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Images</head>
               <p>Add references to images as facsimile references on each <gi>pb</gi> tag, and add
                  a separate facsimiles section where all images are listed, between the TEIheader
                  and body. This will allow you to record multiple images for each page. eg: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <teiHeader>...</teiHeader>
                     <facsimile>
                        <graphic url="lf_liverpoolMuseum_farman_r.jpg"/>
                        <graphic url="lf_liverpoolMuseum_farman_r_1.jpg"/>
                        <graphic url="lf_liverpoolMuseum_farman_r_2.jpg"/>
                        <graphic url="lf_liverpoolMuseum_farman_v.jpg"/>
                     </facsimile>
                     <text>...</text>
                  </egXML>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <lb/>
         <div>
            <head>Encoding Legal Documents</head>

            <div>
               <head>Structure</head>

               <p>We will transcribe and present the text in reading order, so that we offer an
                  edited text which makes sense to readers. However, we can still record the
                  information that it appears elsewhere in the document, and convey that in a
                  hover-over or footnote (see Elevated text section).</p>
               <div>
                  <head>Text divisions</head>
                  <p>We treat the text as made up of different divisions for different textual units
                     within a document. All text must be contained in divs, with language
                        <att>xml:lang</att> and a <att>type</att> as follows. <egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <div xml:lang="per" type="maintext">Example</div>
                     </egXML></p>
                  <p><hi>Possible language values include</hi>: ara (Arabic), ben (Bengali), eng
                     (English), guj (Gujarati), hin (Hindi), mar (Marathi), per (Persian), pan
                     (Punjabi), raj (Rajasthani), urd (Urdu), syl (Sylheti), kan (Kannada), arm
                     (Armenian)</p>
                  <p><hi>Possible types include</hi>: authorisation (for ciphers, seals), maintext
                     (for the primary textual sections of the document), witness (for witness
                     statements), invocation, particulars (for appendix-like enumerations),
                     endorsements (lower level authorisations), clericalNotes, laterAddition,
                     laterTranslation. </p>
                  <p>If a div contains more than one language, tag the words that are foreign to the
                     main language of the div in a <gi>foreign</gi> element, including
                        <att>xml:lang</att>: <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><div
                           xml:lang="per" type="witness">
                           <p>اسحاق <foreign lang="eng">example</foreign> آل محمد</p>
                        </div>
                     </egXML></p>
                  <p>If the text division is located in the margin or in an unusual place on the
                     page, you can record that using <att>rend</att> on <gi>div</gi>, using the
                     following terms 'below; bottom; margin (left, right, or both); top; opposite
                     (i.e. facing); overleaf; above; inline; inspace.</p>
               </div>
               <!-- schema: all divs should have one type/lang only               -->

               <div>
                  <head>Pages, paragraphs, lines</head>
                  <p>Record page beginnings, including numbering and a <att>facs</att> with name of
                     any image file. Give the page an 'n' value that makes sense for the document,
                     eg 1r if it is a single page, 54v if it is the verso of folio 54. The image
                     file should be named similarly: <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <pb n="1r" facs="1661_AC-BRD_1r.jpg"/>
                     </egXML> Use only images of the whole page as the facsimile reference for the
                     page; the separate facsimile section allows you to record more images.</p>
                  <p>Ensure all the text is enclosed in either <gi>p</gi> for paragraphs/prose or
                        <gi>l</gi> for verse. Note that the tags will be typed as they would be for
                     left-to-right languages (ie the first <gi>p</gi> tag will be at the left end of
                     the first line). However, the software will understand that the paragraph
                     begins at the right end of the first line. For headings use the <gi>head</gi>
                     tag within the main text division (These will not be visible on the website
                     until the text display functionality is changed). <egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><div>
                           <head>Heading text</head>
                           <p>Example text</p>
                           <p> نقل فرمان حضرت محی الدین محمد اورنگ زیب عالمگیر بادشاه غازی فی سنه
                              هزار و هفتاد و نه هجری در باب گرفتن خراج</p>
                        </div></egXML></p>
                  <p>Encode serial page numbers using the <gi>fw</gi> forme work tag in the main
                     text division and record its location on the document in <att>place</att>, e.g.
                     "top-right", "bottom-left".</p>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <fw type="pageNum" place="top-right">29</fw>
                  </egXML>



                  <p>Add line beginnings where they appear in the text where there is more than one line. Use <gi>lb</gi> tag: <egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <p><lb/> نقل فرمان حضرت محی الدین محمد <lb/> اورنگ زیب عالمگیر بادشاه غازی
                           فی سنه <lb/>هزار و هفتاد و نه هجری در باب گرفتن خراج </p>
                     </egXML></p>
                  
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Lists</head>
                  <p>Particulars or appendix-like materials are often presented in a list or tabular
                     structure. We aim to reproduce the semantic meaning of this information as a list rather than representing the exact list or tabular structure. 
                     Use line beginning tags to indicate where a new line/number should be. You can use rend=empty to indicate a blank line.
                        <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <list>
                           <lb/><item>a butcher</item>
                           <lb/><item>a baker</item>
                           <lb/><item>a candlestick maker</item>
                        </list>
                        <list>
                           <lb/><item>rings on his fingers</item>
                           <lb/><item>bells on his toes</item>
                        </list>
                     </egXML>
                  </p>
                  <p>For nested lists, see the following example, with optional headings and labels.
                     Note the first item on the main list is itself a list with a label, the second
                     item is another list, and so on: <egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <list>
                           <lb/><head>Optional Heading</head>
                           <lb/><label>Trees</label>
                           <item>
                              <list>
                                 <lb/><item>Rowan</item>
                                 <lb/><item>Birch</item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                           <lb rend="empty"/>
                           <lb/><label>Fruit</label>
                           <item>
                              <list>
                                 <lb/><item>Apple</item>
                                 <lb/><item>Orange</item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </egXML>
                  </p>
                  </div>
            </div>
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Elevated text</head>
               <p>Sometimes the names of a royal person are elevated out of the text as a mark of
                  deference. This should be transcribed where it appears in the reading order. This
                  should be tagged as a person (see below), with an additional <att>rend</att> to
                  specify the position: <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><persName
                        rend="elevated">Example</persName></egXML></p>
            </div>

            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Translations</head>
               <p>All texts will have summaries (see TEI header); some will also have translations.
                  
                  The maintext will be translated, and so will any other sections which are
                  legible/possible to translate. The
                  division is given an id, and the translating div is given a <att>corresp</att>
                  that references it, preceded by hash - the translating div must also be given an
                  id. To create ids use orig for original and trans for translated, underscore, then
                  div1, div2, and so on.. eg: </p>
               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                  <div xml:id="orig_div1" xml:lang="per" type="maintext">
                     <p> تحریر یافت</p>
                  </div>
                  <div corresp="#orig_div1" xml:id="trans_div1">
                     <p>written</p>
                  </div>
               </egXML>
               
            </div>
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Glossing emic terms</head>
               <p>To enable emic terms to appear with either a hover-over gloss in the translation
                  or be hyperlinked to an essay page, or have an explanatory pop-up box, you need to
                  tag the term itself as follows: <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"
                     >according to the <ref type="glossary" target="#gl_chaudhari"
                     >chaudhari</ref></egXML> Next, ensure there is a category for 'chaudhari' and a
                  gloss in the taxonomy.xml document, in the new glossary taxonomy. Ensure that the
                  primary name in the taxonomy list is marked by role=default (usually Persian), and
                  add any other language forms as you prefer. Note the id should be prefixed by gl:
                  for glossary. It is up to the editorial team whether you have a brief note or
                  longer explanation, or include both. You could also add further reading if wanted;
                  capture any information you want here and we can decide how and where to display
                  it later. <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <item xml:id="gl_zimn">
                        <name role="default">zimn</name>
                        <name xml:lang="eng">verso of the document</name>
                        <note>This is where the details of a grant were often entered.</note>
                     </item>
                  </egXML></p>
            </div>
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Special characters, flourishes, elongated letters.</head>
               <p>To use unicode if there is an appropriate unicode symbol.</p>
               <p>The project will include a page that discusses visual organisational features.</p>
               <p>Formulaic phrases and logographs sometimes act as openers and closers to the
                  document.</p>
               <p>Opening flourishes: some flourishes begin the main text as a stand-alone character
                  to indicate a salutation, often they indicate the directionality of the text (who
                  it is sent to/from). These are similar to symbols in witness statements.</p>
               <p>Closing logographs: the special characters the Baiz or Baiza, and faqat,
                  terminate documents. We decided not to tag these as a <gi>closer</gi> but rather
                  to use a specific <gi>g</gi> element to specify which character is used. These
                  will be defined in the Encoding Description in the Header and in an essay on the
                  site. The following examples show how these should appear in original and
                  translations. <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <div>
                        <p>... <g ref="#baiz">بیض</g>
                        </p>
                     </div>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <div>
                        <p>... <g ref="#baiz">Ended</g>
                        </p>
                     </div>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <g ref="#faqat">فقط</g>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <g ref="#faqat">Nothing further</g>
                  </egXML>
               </p>
               <p>For moratab shod closer that appears as a seal (often in Marathi documents), we
                  will encode as a seal with the text of the two words, or occasionally in
                  handwritten form as part of the text. We can add an editorial note in the
                  document. Editorial essay will discuss this element alongside baiz, faqat, and
                  other closers and openers.</p>
               <p>For other character symbols you can just add more <gi>g</gi> forms. For the
                  absence of a number that is quite common in Marathi documents, and representations
                  of fractions, suggest the following for original and translated sections: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <g ref="#ali">[अळी]</g>
                     <g ref="#ali">[fractional symbol]</g>
                  </egXML></p>
               <div>
                  <head>Siyaq accounting shorthand</head>
                  <p>Siyaq is accounting shorthand for numbers, but it is not possible to type the
                     characters or use unicode. Therefore we treat them as glyphs that we
                     transliterate into the relevant number, again using <gi>g</gi>: <egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><g ref="#siyaq">4</g></egXML>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Symbols indicating absence/ending of number</head>
                  <p>Common in Marathi documents, there are symbols denoting absence of a
                     number/that a number is finished, but it is not possible to type the
                     characters, use unicode, or easily transliterate to another character.
                     Therefore we treat these as graphic symbols.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <lb/>

            
            <div>
               <head>Seals and ciphers</head>
               <p>Transcribe seals and ciphers where they appear in the text using the
                     <gi>stamp</gi> element, including any text within the stamp in a
                     <gi>mentioned</gi> element. We are using 'stamp' for convenience, as a marker
                  of authorisation: <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><p>
                        <lb/>بمضمون مسطور مقر مذکور اقرار نمود فقط <lb/><stamp type="seal">Red wax
                              seal<mentioned>فتح الباب من فضل الله</mentioned></stamp>
                        <stamp type="cipher">Red ink cipher<mentioned>فتح الباب من فضل
                              الله</mentioned></stamp>
                     </p></egXML> If there is no text to transcribe, describe the seal in the
                     <gi>stamp</gi> element, but don't use <gi>mentioned</gi>: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><p>
                        <lb/>بمضمون مسطور مقر مذکور اقرار نمود فقط <lb/><stamp type="seal">Elaborate
                           seal with image of Lion</stamp>
                     </p></egXML>
               </p>
            </div>
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Illustrations and figures</head>
               <p> Use <gi>figure</gi> element for illustrations and graphic symbols, especially
                  those in witness statements (e.g. dagger, plough, scissors, sign of the hand). Add
                  a description with <gi>figDesc</gi>. Use concise lower-case descriptions, as
                  below. To optionally indicate where it is located on the page, use
                     <att>place</att>, using the following terms 'below; bottom; margin (left,
                  right, or both); top; opposite (i.e. facing); overleaf; above; inline;
                  inspace.</p>
               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                  <figure place="margin right">
                     <figDesc>dagger</figDesc>
                  </figure>
                  <figure>
                     <figDesc>plough</figDesc>
                  </figure>
               </egXML>
            </div>



            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Editorial notes and bibliographic references</head>
               <p>Editorial notes written by the project team can be added with note element. Type
                  this note where you want a footnote superscript number to appear (the text itself
                  will appear as a footnote or a pop-up).: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><note>The qazi's endorsement appears
                        in the top-left margin.</note></egXML>
               </p>
               <p>You may cite bibliographic references in your note: do this by typing the
                  short-form of the reference, and tagging the reference with <gi>ref</gi>, adding a
                     <att>type</att> = bibl, and a <att>target</att> which gives the xml:id of the
                  reference in the bibliography file, preceded by hash. <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <note>For further discussion with respect to a late-eighteenth century letter
                        from Peshwa Madhavrao Narayan to the Dutch VOC, see <ref type="bibl"
                           target="#bellarykar2019">Bellarykar, "Two Marathi Letters," p.
                        26-7</ref>.</note>
                  </egXML>
               </p>
               <p>
                  To refer to another document or document type, see section 3.12.
               </p>
            </div>
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Abbreviations</head>
               <p> For abbreviations, tag both the abbreviated form of the word and the expanded
                  version. Note that if there is a punctuation mark that indicates the abbreviation,
                  if you are transcribing it, it must be included in the <tag>abbr</tag> tag.
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <choice>
                        <abbr>yr</abbr>
                        <expan>your</expan>
                     </choice>
                  </egXML></p>
               <p>If you don't want to provide an expansion, eg for a word like Mr, then don't tag
                  as an abbreviation.</p>
            </div>
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Deletions, additions, notes made by contemporaries</head>
               <div>
                  <head>Notes and additions</head>
                  <p>Remember that editorial notes made by the project team should be encoded in a
                        <gi>note</gi> element; notes made by contemporaries should be transcribed as
                     normal text, either as part of an existing <gi>div</gi> or if it is an addition
                     to the text, using the <gi>add</gi> element.</p>
                  <p>When showing a word added by the author or a contemporary (as opposed to by you
                     the editor), use <gi>add</gi>: <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        It was written on <add>(day)</add> 15, month zi-al-Qua'da, year 15. </egXML>
                  </p>

               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Deletions</head>
                  <p>When a word or letter has been deleted, use <gi>del</gi>. In the example below,
                     the words "alias Mathura" have been crossed out: <egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <p>in the town of Islamabad, <del>alias Mathura</del>, etc. those (lands)
                           are given in lease (dar wajh-i supurd) to Gosamin</p>
                     </egXML> If the word has been replaced in the text, use <gi>add</gi> also:
                        <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <p>in the town of Islamabad, <del>alias Mathura</del><add>also called
                              M.</add>, etc. those (lands) are given in lease (dar wajh-i supurd) to
                           Gosamin</p>
                     </egXML>
                  </p>
               </div>
            </div>

            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Dates</head>
               <p>Include the date of the document in the TEIHeader (see above)</p>
               <p>Tag any dates mentioned in the body of the text, including the calendar: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><date calendar="#hijri-qamri">9 نهم
                        شهر جمادی الاول سنه ۱۰۷۱ هجری</date></egXML></p>
            </div>
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Other features: measurements, document references</head>
               <p>Tag any references to measurements as follows: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><measure type="currency" unit="rupee"
                        quantity="13">سیزده روپیه</measure></egXML></p>
               <p>If the measure is part of a rate/ratio or something else which you want to record
                  as a group, wrap the measure tags in <gi>measureGrp</gi>, eg: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <measureGrp type="ratio">
                        <measure type="currency" unit="rupee" quantity="30">30 rupees</measure> per
                           <measure type="currency" unit="rupee" quantity="100">100 rupees</measure>
                     </measureGrp>
                  </egXML></p>
               <p>Tag any references to other documents with <gi>ref</gi>, adding a
                  <att>type</att> = document, and a <att>target</att> of the document ID, preceded by hash. 
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <note>It is very strange that the order is to destroy a house but the order is similar to that in <ref type="document" target="#lf_pDas_1660_brd_ac_ii">1660 Order of Nawazish Khan to Purshottam Das granting a house</ref>'. Perhaps old houses were being destroyed.</note>
                  </egXML>
               </p>
               
            </div>
            
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Uncertainty: general</head>
               <p>To indicate uncertainty in your transcription, use <gi>unclear</gi> element. You
                  can also add a footnote offering further detail if wanted:</p>

               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                  <p>in the area of <unclear>Kushk</unclear> on the bank of the river</p>
               </egXML>
               
               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><persName>मोहन</persName>
                  <unclear>कु</unclear> थार अपणी रजा रगवत सु चोध- </egXML>

            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Uncertainty and gaps</head>
               <p>If you have no guess for what the word is, or if it is missing from the source
                  text because of a tear etc, use the <gi>gap</gi> element:</p>
               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                  <p>Example text with <gap/>.</p>
               </egXML>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Uncertainty: multiple possible readings</head>
               <p>If you aren't clear what the word is, but there are multiple possibilities, you
                  can record these using the <gi>app</gi> element:</p>
               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                  <p>is <app><rdg cert="low">allocated</rdg><rdg cert="high">situated</rdg></app> in
                     the town of Islamabad</p>
               </egXML>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Spaces intentionally left blank</head>
               <p>If there is a gap in the transcription because of unclear words or a tear etc, use
                     <gi>gap</gi> as described above. However use <gi>space</gi> wherever it is
                  desired to record an unusual space in the source text, e.g. space left for a word
                  to be filled in later, for later rubrication, etc.</p>
               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">The <space/> day of June
                  1675.</egXML>
            </div>

         </div>
         <lb/>
         <div>
            
            <head>Encoding People, Places, Archival Collections, Works Cited</head>
            <lb/>
            <p> When marking up people and places that have not been encountered previously, you
               will need to create a new entry in the people.xml or places.xml file. If they already
               have an entry in these separate files, simply find it and use its xml:id in the
                  <gi>persName</gi> or <gi>placeName</gi> tag, as explained below. </p>




            <div>
               <head>People</head>
               <p>Encode people's names in the body of the document using <gi>persName</gi>. Look at
                  the people list to find their xml:id, use this preceded by '#' as a
                  <att>ref</att>: <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><persName
                        ref="#nathu">ناتهو</persName></egXML>
               </p>
               <p> Every <gi>persName</gi> should have a <att>ref</att> which references the default
                  name of the person in the separate person list. If the person doesn't have an
                  entry in the person list, create one. </p>
               <p>If readings of person or place names are unclear or illegible, create an entry in
                  people.xml or places.xml using your best guess at the name and add a <gi>note</gi>
                  to explain that it's unclear. In the document itself wrap the persName or
                  placeName element in an <gi>unclear</gi> tag: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><unclear><persName ref="#nathu"
                           >ناتهو</persName></unclear></egXML>
               </p>
               <div>
                  <head>Adding entries to the Person list</head>
                  <p> Whenever a new person is encoded in the documents, you must create a reference
                     to them in the people.xml file within <gi>listPerson</gi>, with the
                        <att>xml:id</att> on the <gi>person</gi> element, which will be used for the
                        <att>ref</att> used in the main text. This should be capitalized and a
                     single word: if you need to disambiguate between multiple people of the same
                     name, use an expanded name where possible e.g. 'virginiaWoolf'.</p>
                  <p> Each person entry must also contain a <gi>persName</gi> element with a
                     relevant <att>xml:lang</att> indicating the language. They may have more than
                     one name across different languages; record that here and choose a default name
                     for the website by adding <tag>@role='default'</tag> - if possible, use the
                     English version as default. </p>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <person xml:id="maqbul">
                        <persName xml:lang="eng" role="default"><name>Maqbul</name></persName>
                        <persName xml:lang="per">مقبول </persName>
                     </person>
                  </egXML>
                  <p>If there are multiple people within the corpus with the same name, they must
                     have different identifiers; if all you know about someone is a single name so
                     you can't give them an expanded name that makes sense e.g.
                        <tag>@xml:id='muhammadSonOfYassein'</tag>, add a number after their name
                     instead, e.g. <tag>@xml:id='muhammad001'</tag></p>
                  <p>For people with several parts to their name, tag as follows: <egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <person xml:id="shahBeg">
                           <persName role="default">
                              <roleName>Judge</roleName>
                              <name>Shah Beg</name>
                              <addName type="honorific">refuge of justice</addName>
                              <addName type="patronym">son of Raji Muhammad, son of
                                 Yassein</addName>
                           </persName>
                        </person>
                     </egXML> Note the difference between a roleName and addName type=honorific
                     here. Other types of additional name could be: <egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><addName type="spousal">wife of
                           Yassein</addName></egXML>
                  </p>
                  <p>To be decided by editorial team whether to encode all language versions using
                        <gi>name</gi> and tagging name parts - it's not necessary for current
                     display but would be richer encoding. Optional, and depends in part on how you
                     want the people pages to display different names.</p>
                  <p>You can record any additional information you have on the person, such as
                     gender and occupation.</p>
                  <p>Record their status as a known or not known individual using 'trait': are they
                     a well-known individual or is there little known about the person? Use Trait
                     element with attributes 'status' and 'key' to specify.</p>
                  <p>Record their status as part of a particular social grouping using 'trait'
                     type=socialGroup.</p>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <person>
                        <persName role="default">
                           <roleName>Lady</roleName>
                           <name>Smith</name>
                        </persName>
                        <sex value="F"/>
                        <trait type="status" key="known"/>
                        <trait type="socialGroup" key="afghans"/>
                        <occupation>Poet</occupation>
                        <note>I can add extra detail here if wanted.</note>
                     </person>
                  </egXML>
                  <p>Record the gender of the person, specifying F(female), M (male), O(other),
                     U(unknown), N (not applicable), as follows, within the <tag>person</tag>
                     tag.</p>

               </div>

            </div>
            <lb/>
            <div>
               <head>Places</head>
               <p>Encode place names in the body of the document using <gi>placeName</gi>: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"><placeName ref="#burhanpur"
                        >برهانپور</placeName></egXML>
               </p>
               <p>Every <gi>placeName</gi> should have a <att>ref</att> which references the default
                  name of the place in the separate places list. If there is no entry for the place
                  in the places list, create one. </p>

               <div>
                  <head>Adding entries to the Places list</head>
                  <p> Whenever a new place is encoded in the documents, you must create a reference
                     to it in the places.xml file, with the <att>xml:id</att> matching the
                        <att>ref</att> used in the main text. The id should be should be the
                     standard name for that place, capitalized/in camelcase, such as LittleHintock,
                     Burhanpur or India.</p>
                  <p> We have divided places into the following hierarchy, from largest to smallest,
                     based on their definition: <list>
                        <item>country or territory</item>
                        <item>province or region (corresp. to prant and suba)</item>
                        <item>division (corresp. to sarkar)</item>
                        <item>district (corresp. to pargana)</item>
                        <item>sub-district (corresp. to taraf, karyat, and mahal)</item>
                        <item>city, town, village (corresp. to mauza, qasba, balda)</item>
                        <item>neighbourhood</item>
                        <item>fort</item>
                        <item>street</item>
                        <item>building</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p> Like person entries, each place entry must also contain at least one
                     <gi>placeName</gi> element with a <gi>name</gi> tag and relevant <att>xml:lang</att>, and a
                        <gi>placeName</gi> for the English translation. Add a <att>type</att> to the
                        <gi>place</gi> element, indicating which of the above categories it
                     falls into.<egXML
                        xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <place xml:id="burhanpur" type="city">
                           <placeName xml:lang="per"><name>برهانپور</name></placeName>
                           <placeName xml:lang="eng"><name>Burhanpur</name></placeName>
                        </place>
                     </egXML>
                  </p>
                  <p>if a placeName encorporates an epithet, like Realm of Light, tag this within the placeName as we do for people names, as an addName type=epithet. This is why you also need to tag the rest of the placeName with <gi>name</gi>, following practice in people file.
                     <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <place xml:id="subaAurangabad" type="province">
                           <placeName xml:lang="per">
                              <addName type="epithet">خجسته بنیاد</addName>
                              <name>اورنگاباد</name>
                           </placeName>
                           <placeName xml:lang="eng">
                              <addName type="epithet">Fortunate Foundation (Khujasta Bunyad)</addName>
                              <name>Aurangabad</name>
                           </placeName>
                           <location>
                              <geo>19.87757 75.34226</geo>
                              <offset type="zoom">5</offset>
                           </location>
                           <note>The coordinates provided are for the city of Aurangabad.</note>
                        </place>
                     </egXML>
                  </p>
                  <p>Location: Add <gi>location</gi> to every place entry. Provide coordinates (if known) in a <gi>geo</gi> tag within
                     <gi>location</gi>, separated by a space, not a comma. Use <gi>offset</gi> with
                     <att>type</att>="zoom" and the corresponding zoom level number depending on place
                     type (see below) to set the correct place map view.
                  <list>
                     <item>region/ province: 5</item>
                     <item>district/ division: 8</item>
                     <item>city/ sub-district: 11</item>
                     <item>town: 13</item>
                     <item>neighbourhood/ village: 14</item>
                     <item>fort/ street: 16</item>
                  </list>
                  </p>

                  <p>Alias: if a place is known by another name, the simplest method is to add this
                     as another <gi>placeName</gi> with the relevant language, and explain their
                     relationship in a note. If this does not suffice, add a separate
                        <gi>addName</gi> tag beneath the existing placeNames, with type=alias.</p>

                  <p>Where possible, add a reference from Geonames in <gi>listBibl</gi> or if there
                     is no entry, give approximate geographical coordinates in <gi>location</gi>.
                     Add notes if wanted. If the place no longer exists, add as a note. 
                     <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                        <place xml:id="khandwa" type="village">
                           <placeName xml:lang="per"><name>کندوهه</name></placeName>
                           <placeName xml:lang="eng"><name>Khandwa</name></placeName>
                           <location>
                              <geo>22.5839 75.64596</geo>
                              <offset type="zoom">14</offset>
                           </location>
                           <note>The identification of this place is tentative.</note>
                           <bibl type="geonames" n="10705333"></bibl>
                        </place>
                     </egXML> NB: if including a note, add this before the listBibl.</p>
               </div>
               
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Social Groupings</head>
               <p>Org stands for organisational name and can be used to refer to any social or
                  ethnic grouping as well as any organisations. At the bottom of the people.xml
                  file, you can use this to record any number of names in different languages, a
                  descriptive note (this will be the paragraph of the essay), and further reading
                  using the listBibl/bibl elements. <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <org xml:id="afghans">
                        <orgName xml:lang="eng">Afghans</orgName>
                        <note>Descriptive note about grouping.</note>
                        <!--    further reading -->
                        <listBibl>
                           <bibl type="academic" n="#exampleFromBibliographyFile"/>
                           <bibl type="wikipedia" n="Afghan_(ethnonym)"/>
                        </listBibl>
                     </org></egXML>
               </p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <head>Archival Collections</head>
               <p>Reference the archival collection in the TEI header, underneath repository,
                  preceded by # (as seen above). Ensure that the archival collections are recorded
                  as entities in the repositories file, within the archival collections list. You
                  can use this to record name, a descriptive note (this will be the paragraph of the
                  essay), and further reading using the listBibl/bibl elements. <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <item xml:id="pDas">
                        <name>P Das collection</name>
                        <note>Descriptive note.</note>
                        <!--    further reading -->
                        <listBibl>
                           <bibl type="academic" n="#chatterjee2020"/>
                        </listBibl>
                     </item>
                  </egXML>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Works Cited</head>
               <p>When creating bibliographic entries in bibliography_repositories.xml, format
                  entries according to the type of reference, see examples below.</p>
               <div>
                  <head>Primary source</head>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <bibl xml:id="mukhlis2013">
                        <author>
                           <surname>Mukhlis</surname>
                           <forename>Anand Ram</forename>
                        </author>
                        <author>
                           <surname>Shekhar</surname>
                           <forename>Chander</forename>
                        </author>
                        <author>
                           <surname>Ghelichkhani</surname>
                           <forename>Hamidreza</forename>
                        </author>
                        <author>
                           <surname>Yousefdahi</surname>
                           <forename>Houman</forename>
                        </author>
                        <title level="m">Mirat al-Istilah</title>
                        <pubPlace>New Delhi</pubPlace>
                        <publisher>National Missions for Manuscripts</publisher>
                        <date when="2013">2013</date>
                     </bibl>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Journal article</head>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <bibl xml:id="bellarykar2019">
                        <author>
                           <surname>Bellarykar</surname>
                           <forename>Nikhil</forename>
                        </author>
                        <title level="a">Two Marathi Letters from the Arsip Nasional Republik
                           Indonesia: A Snapshot of Dutch-Maratha Relations in the
                           Late-Eighteenth-Century Coromandel</title>
                        <title level="j">Itinerario</title>
                        <date when="2019">2019</date>
                        <biblScope unit="vol">44</biblScope>
                        <biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
                        <biblScope unit="part">14-31</biblScope>
                        <ref type="url">https://doi.org/10.1017/S0165115319000032</ref>
                     </bibl>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Chapter in book entry</head>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <bibl xml:id="habib1990">
                        <author>
                           <surname>Habib</surname>
                           <forename>Irfan</forename>
                        </author>
                        <editor/>
                        <title level="a">Merchant Communities in Precolonial India</title>
                        <title level="m">The Rise of Merchant Empires: Long-Distance Trade in the
                           Early Modern World, 1350–1750</title>
                        <pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
                        <publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
                        <date when="1990">1990</date>
                     </bibl>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Encyclopaedia entry</head>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <bibl xml:id="diplomatic2012">
                        <author>
                           <surname>Björkman</surname>
                           <forename>W.</forename>
                        </author>
                        <author>
                           <surname>Colin</surname>
                           <forename>G.S.</forename>
                        </author> 
                        <author>
                           <surname>Busse</surname>
                           <forename>H.</forename>
                        </author>, 
                        <author>
                           <surname>Reychmann</surname>
                           <forename>J.</forename>
                        </author>
                        <author>
                           <surname>Zajaczkowski</surname>
                           <forename>A.</forename>
                        </author>
                        <title level="a">Diplomatic</title>
                        <title level="m">Encyclopaedia of Islam</title>
                        <edition>2</edition>
                        <date when="2012">2012</date>
                        <ref type="url"
                           >https://referenceworks-brillonline-com.uoelibrary.idm.oclc.org/entries/encyclopaedia-of-islam-2/*-COM_0169</ref>
                     </bibl>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Dictionary</head>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <bibl xml:id="steingass1892">
                        <author>
                           <surname>Steingass</surname>
                           <forename>Francis Joseph</forename>
                        </author>
                        <title level="m">A Comprehensive Persian-English dictionary, including the
                           Arabic words and phrases to be met with in Persian literature</title>
                        <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
                        <publisher>Routledge &amp; K. Paul</publisher>
                        <date when="1892">1892</date>
                        <ref type="url">https://dsal.uchicago.edu/dictionaries/steingass/</ref>
                     </bibl>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Blog post</head>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <bibl xml:id="ajamMC">
                        <editor>
                           <surname>Lutfi</surname>
                           <forename>Ameem</forename>
                        </editor>
                        <editor>
                           <surname>Stephenson</surname>
                           <forename>Lindsey</forename>
                        </editor>
                        <title level="a">Reimagining Baloch “Mercenaries” in the Western Indian
                           Ocean</title>
                        <publisher>Ajam Media Collective</publisher>
                        <date when="2020-08-17">17 August 2020</date>
                        <ref type="url"
                           >https://ajammc.com/2020/08/17/ajam-podcast-21-baloch-indian-ocean/</ref>
                     </bibl>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Unpublished manuscript</head>
                  <p>Use <gi>availability</gi> for any information about the availability of the
                     text such as restrictions on use, distribution, copyright or licence status.
                     For more general information use <gi>note</gi>. Both are optional.</p>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <bibl xml:id="skinnerTashrih">
                        <author>
                           <surname>Skinner</surname>
                           <forename>James</forename>
                        </author>
                        <title level="u">Tashrih al-aqwam</title>
                        <msIdentifier>
                           <repository ref="#bl"/>
                           <idno>Add. 27455</idno>
                        </msIdentifier>
                        <biblScope unit="page">143 r-v</biblScope>
                        <ref type="url">https://imagesonline.bl.uk/asset/9017</ref>
                        <availability>Unpublished manuscript, copy available through the British
                           Library.</availability>
                     </bibl>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
               <div>
                  <head>Translated Sources</head>
                  <p>To include a translator in a reference, use <gi>editor</gi> with an attribute @role="translator". The rest of the entry can be formatted following the examples above.</p>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <bibl xml:id="skinnerTashrih">
                        <author>
                           <surname>Skinner</surname>
                           <forename>James</forename>
                        </author>
                        <editor role="translator">
                           <surname>Hypothetical surname</surname>
                           <forename>Hypothetical first name</forename>
                        </editor>
                        <title level="u">Tashrih al-aqwam</title>
                        <msIdentifier>
                           <repository ref="#bl"/>
                           <idno>Add. 27455</idno>
                        </msIdentifier>
                        <biblScope unit="page">143 r-v</biblScope>
                        <ref type="url">https://imagesonline.bl.uk/asset/9017</ref>
                        <availability>Unpublished manuscript, copy available through the British
                           Library.</availability>
                     </bibl>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Further reading sources and bibliography</head>
               <p>This section applies to people, places, document types and archival collections.
                  If your person is relatively well-known, they may have an entry in the Virtual
                  International Authority File, Library of Congress Name Authority File, WorldCat,
                  International Standard Name Identifier, or on Wikipedia that you can link to. You
                  may want to reference academic books/articles or other websites too as further
                  reading for these entities. </p>
               <p>Add a <tag>listBibl</tag> tag at the end of the entry for the person, place,
                  document type, social group or archival collection. Note that there is no longer
                  any need to add a type to listBibl.</p>
               <p>Within this, add a <tag>bibl</tag> element with a <att>type</att> attribute
                  'viaf', or similar and then give it an <att>n</att> attribute, with the value
                  being the relevant number or reference to the relevant entry. If adding a
                  Wikipedia link to a <tag>person</tag> entry, use <att>type</att> of "wikipedia",
                  and so on. The <att>n</att> attribute should be the final part of the URL of the
                  Wikipedia entry, as follows.</p>
               <p>Adding a wikipedia link will mean we can display the person's image from their
                  wikipedia page.</p>
               <p>Note that for academic sources, you should add the id of the academic source as
                  listed in the bibliography file as the <att>n</att> value, preceded by hash. If
                  there is no entry for the academic writing in the bibliography file, add one.</p>
               <p>See the examples below:</p>
               <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                  <listBibl>
                     <bibl type="viaf" n="54148778"/>
                     <bibl type="wikipedia" n="Elizabeth_Martha_Brown"/>
                     <bibl type="academic" n="#chatterjee2020"/>
                     <bibl type="website" n="www.example.com"/>
                  </listBibl>
               </egXML>
               <p>To give a relevant page range, use biblScope in the bibl element here and not in
                  the full bibliographic entry, as follows: <egXML
                     xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples">
                     <listBibl>
                        <bibl type="academic" n="#chatterjee2020"
                           ><biblScope>pp.44-46</biblScope></bibl>
                     </listBibl>
                  </egXML></p>
            </div>
         </div>

      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
